<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
    Copyright 2015-2017 F5 Networks, Inc.
   
    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at
   
        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
   
    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
 -->

<feature
      id="com.f5.irule.feature"
      label="F5 Programmability for Eclipse"
      version="2.0.0.qualifier"
      provider-name="F5 Networks">

   <description url="http://devcentral.f5.com/irules">
      F5 Programmability Development Environment for Eclipse
   </description>

   <copyright url="http://devcentral.f5.com/irules">
      ©F5 Networks, Inc. 
   </copyright>

   <license url="http://devcentral.f5.com/irules">
F5 Networks END USER LICENSE AGREEMENT 
2016-03-21 
DOC-0395-02 
IMPORTANT - READ BEFORE INSTALLING OR OPERATING THIS PRODUCT 
***************************************************************** 

LICENSEE AGREES TO BE BOUND BY THE TERMS OF THIS END USER LICENSE 
AGREEMENT (“LICENSE”) BY INSTALLING, HAVING INSTALLED, COPYING, OR 
OTHERWISE USING THE PRODUCT. IF LICENSEE DOES NOT AGREE, DO NOT INSTALL 
OR USE THE PRODUCT.  


1. Scope.  This License applies to the software product ("Software") 
you have licensed from F5. This License is a legal agreement between F5 
and the single entity ("Licensee") that has acquired the Software from 
F5 under these terms and conditions. All references to “F5” in this 
License will be deemed to be a reference to the applicable F5 entity as 
follows: (i) if Licensee’s primary place of business is located in the 
European Economic Area, the Middle East or Africa (“EMEA”), the F5 
entity is F5 Networks Ltd.; (ii) if Licensee’s primary place of 
business is located in the Asia-Pacific region, excluding Japan, India 
and Taiwan (“APAC”), the F5 entity is F5 Networks Singapore Pte. Ltd.; 
and (iii) if Licensee’s primary place of business is located in Japan, 
India, Taiwan or a region outside of EMEA or APAC, the F5 entity is F5 
Networks, Inc.  The Software incorporates certain third party software 
programs subject to the terms and restrictions of the applicable 
licenses identified herein.  

2. License Grant.  Subject to the terms of this License, F5 grants to 
Licensee a perpetual, non-exclusive, non-transferable license to use 
the Software in object code form for Licensee's internal business 
purposes.  Other than as specifically described herein, no right or 
license is granted to any of F5's trademarks, patents, copyrights, or 
other intellectual property rights and F5 retains all rights not 
granted herein.  The Software incorporates certain third party 
software, which is used subject to licenses from the respective 
owners.  The third party software is identified in the Software 
documentation available at http://askf5.com. The protections given to 
F5 under this License also apply to the suppliers of this third party 
software.  

3. Restrictions. 


(a) The Software, Software documentation and the associated copyrights 
and other intellectual property rights are owned by F5 or its licensors 
and are protected by law and international treaties.  Licensee may not 
copy or translate the Software documentation provided with the Software 
or available online at http://askf5.com ("Documentation") without F5's 
prior, written consent.  Licensee may install, use, access, display and 
run the Software only in the manner in which it has been licensed as 
indicated herein and in the applicable purchase order, quote or the 
license file for such Product or Software, including but not limited to 
any restrictions on number of protected applications, number or type of 
licensed devices, number of authorized copies or instances, number of 
users, bandwidth, non-production use, database or location 
restrictions.  Licensee agrees that it will not defeat, circumvent or 
disable any copy protection mechanism or mechanism in the Software used 
to limit license duration or access to non-licensed functionality or 
capacity, and that any such attempt will be a material breach of this 
Agreement.  F5 reserves the right to audit Licensee's use of the 
Software or authorize others to conduct such an audit on its behalf and 
to disable any application or functionality that has not been 
specifically licensed, in addition to any other rights and remedies 
available to F5. 

(b) Certain portions of the Software include third party software modules 
as identified in the applicable Software documentation.  

(c) Licensee may not copy (except to make one archival copy for backup 
and disaster recover purposes), modify, sell, sub-license, rent or 
transfer the Software or any associated Software documentation to any 
third party.  Licensee may not disassemble, reverse compile or reverse 
engineer the Software or encourage others to do so except as required 
by law for interoperability purposes, and then only after Licensee has 
given F5 an opportunity to provide information or software necessary to 
resolve such interoperability issues. 

4. Export Control.  To the extent applicable, Licensee agrees to comply 
with the Export Administration Act, the Export Control Act, all 
regulations promulgated under such Acts, and all other US government 
regulations relating to the export of technical data and equipment and 
products produced therefrom which are applicable to Licensee.  In 
countries other than the US, Licensee agrees to comply with the local 
regulations regarding importing, exporting or using cryptographic software 
if applicable. Licensee agrees it will not export or re-export the 
Software to any country, person, or entity subject to U.S. export 
restrictions. Specifically, Licensee agrees not to export or re-export the 
Software: (i) to any country to which the U.S. has embargoed or restricted 
the export of goods or services, or to any national of any such country, 
wherever located, who intends to transmit or transport the Software back 
to such country; (ii) to any person or entity who Licensee knows or has 
reason to know will utilize the Software or portion thereof in the design, 
development or production of nuclear, chemical or biological weapons; or  
(iii) to any person or entity who has been prohibited from participating 
in U.S. export transactions by any federal agency of the U.S. government, 
including but not limited to anyone on the U.S. Treasury Department's list 
of Specially Designated Nationals or the U.S. Department of Commerce's 
Table of Denial Orders. By installing or using the Software, Licensee 
represents and warrants that it is not located in, under control of, or a 
national or resident of any such country or on any such list.  

5. Notice to U.S. Government End Users.  The Software and Documentation 
qualify as "commercial items," as that term is defined at Federal 
Acquisition Regulation ("FAR") (48 C.F.R.) 2.101, consisting of 
"commercial computer software" and "commercial computer software 
documentation" as such terms are used in FAR 12.212. Consistent with 
FAR 12.212 and DoD FAR Supp. 227.7202-1 through 227.7202-4, and 
notwithstanding any other FAR or other contractual clause to the 
contrary in any agreement into which this End User License Agreement 
may be incorporated, Licensee may provide to Government end user or, if 
this Agreement is direct, Government end user will acquire, the 
Software and Software documentation with only those rights set forth in 
this End User License Agreement. Use of either the Software or Software 
documentation or both constitutes agreement by the Government that the 
Software and Documentation are "commercial computer software" and 
"commercial computer software documentation" and constitutes acceptance 
of the rights and restrictions herein.  

6. DISCLAIMER; LIMITATION OF REMEDY.  F5 AND ITS THIRD PARTY LICENSORS 
DISCLAIM ANY AND ALL WARRANTIES AND GUARANTEES, EXPRESS, IMPLIED OR 
OTHERWISE, ARISING, WITH RESPECT TO THE SOFTWARE, DATA, SPECIFICATIONS, 
OR DOCUMENTATION DELIVERED HEREUNDER, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE 
WARRANTY OF MERCHANTABILITY, WARRANTY OF NON-INFRINGEMENT OR TITLE AND 
THE WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  F5 MAKES NO WARRANTY 
CONCERNING THE COMPLETENESS OR ACCURACY OF THE DATA OR INFORMATION 
OBTAINED OR DERIVED THROUGH THE USE OF THE DATA INCLUDED IN THE 
SOFTWARE AND THE DATA IS PROVIDED "AS IS". IN NO EVENT DOES F5 WARRANT 
THAT THE SOFTWARE IS ERROR FREE, THAT IT WILL OPERATE WITH ANY SOFTWARE 
OR HARDWARE OTHER THAN THAT PROVIDED BY F5 OR SPECIFIED IN THE 
DOCUMENTATION, OR THAT THE SOFTWARE WILL SATISFY LICENSEE'S OWN 
SPECIFIC REQUIREMENTS. F5 HAS NOT AUTHORIZED ANYONE TO MAKE ANY 
REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OTHER THAN AS PROVIDED ABOVE OR TO 
OTHERWISE MODIFY THE TERMS OF THIS LICENSE.  THE COLLECTIVE LIABILITY 
OF F5 AND ITS THIRD PARTY LICENSORS UNDER THIS LICENSE WILL BE LIMITED 
TO THE AMOUNT PAID FOR THE PRODUCT.  F5 AND ITS THIRD PARTY LICENSORS 
WILL NOT HAVE ANY OBLIGATION OR LIABILITY, WHETHER ARISING IN CONTRACT 
(INCLUDING WARRANTY), TORT (INCLUDING ACTIVE, PASSIVE OR IMPUTED 
NEGLIGENCE, STRICT LIABILITY OR PRODUCT LIABILITY) OR OTHERWISE FOR ANY 
PUNITIVE, EXEMPLARY, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR INDIRECT 
DAMAGES,INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF USE, LOSS OF DATA, 
BUSINESS INTERRUPTION, LOSS OF REVENUE, LOSS OF BUSINESS OR OTHER 
FINANCIAL LOSS ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR 
OTHER GOODS OR SERVICES FURNISHED TO LICENSEE BY F5, EVEN IF ADVISED OF 
THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, F5'S 
THIRD PARTY LICENSORS WILL NOT HAVE ANY LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT 
DAMAGES OF ANY KIND UNDER THIS LICENSE AGREEMENT.  THE LIMITATIONS 
CONTAINED IN THIS SECTION WILL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF AN 
ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY LIMITED REMEDY PROVIDED UNDER ANY TERM OF THIS 
AGREEMENT.  SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE LIMITATION OR EXCLUSION 
OF LIABILITY FOR INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES. IN THOSE 
JURISDICTIONS, SUCH INAPPLICABILITY WILL NOT AFFECT THE REMAINDER OF 
THE PROVISIONS IN THIS SECTION.  


7. Termination.  The license granted in Section 2 is effective until 
terminated and will automatically terminate if Licensee fails to comply 
with any of the terms and conditions set forth herein.  Upon termination, 
Licensee will destroy the Software and Software documentation and all 
copies or portions thereof.  

8. Support.  Maintenance and support of the Software is not provided 
under this License.  

9. Miscellaneous.  This License will be governed and construed in 
accordance with the following governing law (“Governing Law”), 
depending on the applicable licensing F5 entity, without regard to its 
choice of law rules:  

Location: F5 Networks Singapore Pte. Ltd. 
Governing Law: The laws of Singapore 
Venue: Singapore 

Location: F5 Networks Ltd. 
Governing Law: The laws of England and Wales 
Venue: London England 

Location: F5 Networks, Inc. 
Governing Law: The laws of the State of Washington 
Venue: Seattle, Washington  

The provisions of the U.N. Convention for the International Sale of Goods 
and the Uniform Computer Information Transactions Act, in whatever form 
adopted, will not apply and the parties specifically opt out of the 
application of such laws.  In the event of any dispute arising out of 
or relating to this Agreement, the parties shall seek to settle the 
dispute via direct discussions.  If a dispute cannot be settled through 
direct discussions, the parties agree to first endeavor to settle the 
dispute via voluntary non-binding mediation, before resorting to 
arbitration.  A mediator will be selected by voluntary agreement of 
both parties, or in the event both parties cannot agree on a mediator, 
a mediator will be selected in accordance with the rules of JAMS.  The 
mediation shall be held in the applicable venue (“Venue”) identified in 
the chart above.  Each party shall bear its own costs and expenses and 
an equal share of the administrative and other fees associated with the 
mediation.  Any dispute that remains unresolved following mediation 
shall be settled by arbitration administered by the JAMS in accordance 
with its Comprehensive Arbitration Rules.  The place of arbitration 
shall be the applicable Venue.  Judgment upon the award rendered by the 
arbitrator(s) may be entered in any court having jurisdiction thereof.  
The arbitrator(s) shall award to the prevailing party, if any, as 
determined by the arbitrator(s), all of its costs and fees.  "Costs and 
fees" mean all reasonable pre-award expenses of the arbitration, 
including the arbitrators' fees, administrative fees, travel expenses, 
out-of-pocket expenses such as copying and telephone, court costs, 
witness fees, and attorneys' fees.  In rendering the award, the 
arbitrator(s) shall determine the rights and obligations of the parties 
according to the substantive and procedural laws of the applicable 
Governing Law.  The foregoing alternative dispute resolution provisions 
will not apply to claims or actions related to the infringement, 
misappropriation or violation of F5’s intellectual property rights or 
those of its third party licensors and such actions may be brought in 
any court of competent jurisdiction.  Any provisions found to be 
unenforceable will not affect the enforceability of the other 
provisions contained herein, but will instead be replaced with a 
provision as similar in meaning to the original as possible.  This 
License constitutes the entire agreement between the parties with 
regard to its subject matter.  No modification will be binding unless 
in writing and signed by the parties.  

10. Acknowledgements.  The Software includes software developed by 
third parties subject to separate licenses.  Please refer to the 
Acknowledgement section found in the Software documentation available 
at http://askf5.com.  

11. Open Source Components. Certain portions of the Software ("Open 
Source Components") are licensed under the terms of applicable open 
source licenses, such as the BSD license, Apache license, the Lesser 
GNU General Public License, the GNU General Public License or any other 
such license.  Information identifying the Open Source Components, and 
the licenses that apply to them, is available in the Software 
documentation available at http://askf5.com.  Your use of each Open 
Source Component is subject to the terms of each applicable license.  
Any other software code that is not part of the Open Source Components 
is subject to the restrictions set forth elsewhere in this License.  
Furthermore, those portions of the Software that are part of the Open 
Source Components are subject to the remaining terms and conditions of 
the License to the extent that those terms are not inconsistent with 
the terms of the applicable licenses of the Open Source Components.  
   </license>

   <plugin
         id="com.f5.irule.model"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="com.f5.irule.ui"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="com.f5.irule.core"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

</feature>
